<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-09T18:09:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@aberdeendevelopers.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[October 2016 Meeting - Keith Davidson]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/october-2016-meeting-keith-davidson"/>
    <updated>2016-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/october-2016-meeting-keith-davidson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Keith Davidson, on Thursday 20th October 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>BreezeJS</strong></p>

<p>BreezeJS is a free, open source JavaScript library that helps you manage data in rich client applications. If you store data in a database, query and save those data as complex object graphs, and share these graphs across multiple screens of your JavaScript client, Breeze is for you. This presentation will introduce BreezeJs and demonstrate some of it&rsquo;s advantages.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-october-2016-meeting-tickets-28505462606?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - October 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Keith Davidson has been programming web sites and apps since the late 90&rsquo;s and started his professional development career in 2000, writing applications with consulting firm Accenture.  He is currently a Senior Software Developer with Petrofac.  When not trying to keep up with the latest web technologies or contributing to open source projects, he enjoys tinkering with Raspberry Pi and Arduino platforms and occasionally plays the drums.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 20th October 2016</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration</li>
<li>1825 - 1830: Introduction</li>
<li>1830 - 1930: BreezeJS</li>
<li>1930 - 2000: Q&amp;A and Prize Draw</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N311, The Sir Ian Wood Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7GJ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/The+Sir+Ian+Wood+Building,+Garthdee+Rd,+Aberdeen+AB10+7GJ">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[September 2016 Meeting - Colin Mackay]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/september-2016-meeting-colin-mackay"/>
    <updated>2016-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/september-2016-meeting-colin-mackay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Colin Mackay, on Thursday 15th September 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Storymapping for Beginners</strong></p>

<p>Sometimes it is difficult to work out how to prioritise the backlog and effectively work iteratively while still holding on to the big picture. What do you put in your MVP (Minimal Viable Product)? What then goes in each incremental release to give your users more and more useful functionality? Storymapping is a technique for solving this problem and getting your solution to your users faster.</p>

<p>In this highly interactive session I&rsquo;ll explain how you go about creating a story map and I&rsquo;ll get you to create one. Lots of sticky notes later you should have a fairly good grasp and be able to use the same technique on your own projects to better manage your backlog and keep everyone aware of the big picture while still working on individual stories.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-september-2016-meeting-tickets-27403321071?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - September 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Colin Mackay was C# MVP for 4 years (2007, 2008, 2009, 2010), and Code Project MVP (for 5 years) and, as of writing, is in the top 3% of StackOverflow users. He runs Scottish Developers and organises DDD Scotland.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 15th September 2016</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration</li>
<li>1825 - 1830: Introduction</li>
<li>1830 - 1930: Storymapping for Beginners</li>
<li>1930 - 2000: Q&amp;A and Prize Draw</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N310, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy - Brightree - Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-brightree-aberdeen"/>
    <updated>2016-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-brightree-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers have been asked to promote the following job vacancy at Brightree in Aberdeen. If you are interested in the position, please contact douglas dot cameron at aberdeendevelopers dot co dot uk (replacing the at and dot with @ and . respectively, trying to stop those nasty spiders getting my email address). Details of the role are as follows:</p>

<hr />

<p>Brightree, the fastest growing cloud based business management solution in the U.S. healthcare market, are seeking UK based team-players to join their expanding Aberdeen office.</p>

<p>The ideal candidates have a propensity to share concepts and techniques as well as foster and encourage sharing of knowledge. You will participate in the technical design of the solutions including data modeling, functional design, test criteria, user interface design and development. Practical, relevant experience as a creative problem solver and a proven ability to convert specifications into exception software solutions are critical.</p>

<p><strong>Primary Duties:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Develop new software features</li>
<li>Maintain existing code through defect correction and refactoring</li>
<li>Participate in technical design</li>
<li>DB design/changes</li>
<li>Provide unit tests for all code</li>
<li>Conduct code reviews with other developers</li>
<li>Follow best practices for software development in a cloud based environment</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Basic Qualifications:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Experience working for a software company with web-based applications using Microsoft technologies.</li>
<li>Knowledge of C# or VB.net, ASP.NET and web technologies such as Web API, WCF, JavaScript, CSS, HTML and Ajax.</li>
<li>Experience with MS SQL Server (TSQL/SQL)</li>
<li>OO knowledge and practical experience of design patterns etc</li>
<li>Practical experience with source code configuration, versioning and promotion</li>
<li>Excellent problem solving, issue identification and technical documentation skills</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple concurrent priorities and meeting deadlines</li>
<li>Strong interpersonal and communication skills</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Preferred Requirements:</strong>
- Experience using VS 2015, SQL Server, Xamarin, .net 4.0/4.5 techniques a plus
- Agile software methodology experience a plus
- Experience working in a SaaS model a plus</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[August 2016 Meeting - Steven Chalmers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/august-2016-meeting-steven-chalmers"/>
    <updated>2016-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/august-2016-meeting-steven-chalmers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Steven Chalmers, on Thursday 18th August 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Experiences of using an Azure website and database in Production</strong></p>

<p>Having developed an Azure website for an internal company tool that is used daily by 30 people across multiple sites, I will cover my experiences of using Azure for over a year.</p>

<p>I will share:</p>

<ul>
<li>Reasons why</li>
<li>Setup and running costs</li>
<li>Features and tools of the Azure websites and Azure Databases</li>
<li>Performance, architecture and coding worries and solutions</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-august-2016-meeting-tickets-26706378497?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - August 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Steven Chalmers has been programming on many different computers and embedded systems since the late 70&rsquo;s. From typing in bytes, assembly all the way through to c#. Currently using ASP.NET MVC, Telerik tools on Azure at work but at home its having fun with his kids by game programming in Roblox.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 18th August 2016</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration</li>
<li>1825 - 1830: Introduction</li>
<li>1830 - 1930: Experiences of using an Azure website and database in Production</li>
<li>1930 - 2000: Q&amp;A and Prize Draw</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N310, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 2016 Meeting - Mike Taulty]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/july-2016-meeting-mike-taulty"/>
    <updated>2016-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/july-2016-meeting-mike-taulty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Mike Taulty, on Thursday 21th July 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>A Platform for More Personal Computing?</strong></p>

<p>Salt and pepper. Fish and chips. Starsky and Hutch. Windows and PC.</p>

<p>Just as Windows became intrinsically linked with personal computing, Microsoft is working to make that just-over-the-horizon leap towards natural interaction and ‘More Personal Computing’ (MPC). It’s already surfacing today in technologies like ‘Cortana’ and ‘Windows Hello’.</p>

<p>In this session, we’ll take a demo-based approach to look at some of the MPC technologies that Windows developers already have available to them in the Universal Windows Platform and some additional technologies out in the cloud under the banner of ‘Microsoft Cognitive Services’</p>

<p>We’ll look at some things with pens, touch, speech, facial recognition, speaker identification and we’ll see what the Windows 10 app platform has to offer developers building modern apps with an ever-more personal touch.</p>

<p>You should expect Visual Studio, C# code and XAML UI and most of the talk will build up an application from scratch adding features as we go along.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-july-2016-meeting-tickets-26418169456?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - July 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Mike Taulty works in the Developer and Platform Group at Microsoft in the UK where he has spent the past few years helping developers understand and get the best from the Microsoft platform. Prior to this, Mike spent 3 years with Microsoft Consulting Services as a consultant on developer technologies.</p>

<p>Before joining Microsoft, Mike spent the previous 9 years working as a software developer for a number of enterprises, consultancies and software vendors working with a variety of operating system, client, communication and server technologies. You can find more of a complete career history over on <a href="http://uk.linkedin.com/in/mtaulty">LinkedIn</a>.</p>

<p>Mike holds a BSc Hons (1st Class) in Computer Science from the University of Leeds.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 21th July 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: A Platform for More Personal Computing?
+ 1930 - 2000: Q&amp;A and Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N309, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[May 2016 Meeting - Kendall Miller]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/may-2016-meeting-kendall-miller"/>
    <updated>2016-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/may-2016-meeting-kendall-miller</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Kendall Miller, on Thursday 12th May 2016 at Aberdeen University&rsquo;s Meston Building.</p>

<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> Please take extra notice of the venue above!  Due to exams happening in our normal RGU venue, this talk will be being hosted by Aberdeen University, in the Meston Building.  Full details of the location can be found below.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>To The Cloud! How Azure helped us improve the scalability of our SaaS</strong></p>

<p>Last year we had to make a decision whether to double down with new hardware in our Colo or go another way to grow our SaaS. In this talk we&rsquo;ll walk through the challenges we&rsquo;ve faced moving from our own hardware to Azure including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Taking advantage of auto-scaling to reduce costs.</li>
<li>Growing 100x without controlling the hardware.</li>
<li>When it all goes wrong and Azure falls over.</li>
<li>How Azure has improved the performance of our on-premises installs too</li>
</ul>


<p>Far from a theoretical conversation about how you could use the cloud, we&rsquo;ll share real data from our production implementation, both the good and the bad. Finally, we&rsquo;ll talk about where we&rsquo;re going with what we&rsquo;ve learned.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-may-2016-meeting-tickets-24846287916?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - May 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Kendall Miller is one of the founding partners of Gibraltar Software, an Independent Software Vendor (ISV) that develops &amp; markets commercial applications for .NET developers. Introduced commercially in 2009, Loupe is an application logging &amp; monitoring platform that is currently used by customers around the world from individual consultants through Fortune 100 companies and governments. Before starting Gibraltar Software, Kendall worked for multiple startups leading their technology development from beginning through profitability. In each case he&rsquo;s focused on translating enterprise-level performance and capabilities down to smaller companies. Kendall has a B.S in Computer Engineering from the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 12th May 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: To The Cloud! How Azure helped us improve the scalability of our SaaS
+ 1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Meston Building (Enter via North Entrance), University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, AB24 3UE</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/viewer?mid=zy5sr2VnGJ2w.khFsoArRBh_Y&amp;hl=en">Meston Building</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[April 2016 Meeting - Gary Ewan Park]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/april-2016-meeting-gary-ewan-park"/>
    <updated>2016-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/april-2016-meeting-gary-ewan-park</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Gary Ewan Park, on Thursday 21st April 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Having your Cake, and eating to too!</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script for your application, but been faced with learning a new language, or DSL, or writing more XML than any person should ever need to?</li>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script that will work cross platform?</li>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script that has first class support for the most common build tools like XUnit, WiX, SignTool, and many others?</li>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script that uses a language that you already know, and love?</li>
</ul>


<p>If you have answered yes to any of these questions, then the Cake (<a href="http://cakebuild.net/">http://cakebuild.net/</a>) Build Automation System is for you!</p>

<p>In this session we will start with a standard .Net Solution and incrementally add a build and orchestration script to compile the application, run unit tests, perform static analysis, package the application, and more, using the C# skills that you may already have.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-april-2016-meeting-tickets-24528759179?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - April 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong>
Gary Ewan Park has been developing on the .Net Platform for almost 9 years. His day job sees him developing using ASP.NET, AngularJS, and WPF, for Oil Companies working in the North Sea.</p>

<p>In his spare time, Gary contributes to a number of Open Source projects including Chocolatey, Boxstarter, Cake, psake and GitVersion.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday,  21st April 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: Having your Cake, and eating to too!
+ 1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N309, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[March 2016 Meeting - Christos Matskas]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2016-meeting-christos-matskas"/>
    <updated>2016-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2016-meeting-christos-matskas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Christos Matskas, on Thursday 24th March 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Microsoft’s ASP.NET Core 1.0 is going to rock your world</strong></p>

<p>ASP.NET Core has been rewritten from the ground up to be the best web development platform for Windows, Mac, and Linux. You can now use your favorite editor to create faster, leaner and more memory efficient ASP.NET applications that work everywhere. In this session, you&rsquo;ll get an introduction to the major advancements and an overview of what&rsquo;s changed and what&rsquo;s stayed the same. You&rsquo;ll also get the chance to see how you can leverage all the new front-end tooling like npm, Bower, Grunt and Gulp to manage your application. This is going to be session full of demos and information that promises to rock your world!</p>

<p>In addition, Christos will be presented a bonus lightning talk entitled:</p>

<p><strong>Becoming an awesome Open Source contributor</strong></p>

<p>Are you a developer that wants to give back to the open source community? Perhaps you&rsquo;re already a seasoned contributor but you want to get better? Or you want to join the open source movement because, well, OSS is the future? Just look at all the cool tech built with OSS: Node.js, BootStrap, ASP.NET etc. Join Christos Matskas to learn about the many ways to contribute, key development tools in OSS projects and tips about what it takes to become a succesful first time contributor and collaborator in this welcoming and open community.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-march-2016-meeting-tickets-21670650499?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=21670650499" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - March 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Christos Matskas is a software consultant, author, blogger and speaker. A Microsoft MVP on Visual Studio and Development Technologies, he&rsquo;s a passionate Open Source advocate and a regular contributor to numerous projects. His portfolio includes collaborations with some of the biggest companies in the industry such as MarkIT, Lockheed Martin and Barclays. He&rsquo;s been building software for over 12 years and loves to work closely with the community through speaking at conferences, mentoring and teaching programs.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday,  24th March 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: Microsoft’s ASP.NET Core 1.0 is going to rock your world.
+ 1930 - 1945: Bonus Lightning Talk - Becoming an awesome Open Source contributor
+ 1945 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N309, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ScotNetRocks! Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/scotnetrocks-aberdeen"/>
    <updated>2016-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/scotnetrocks-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present the final night of the ScotNetRocks! tour, hopefully you’ll be able to join us to hear Carl and Richard kick off the evening as they take us on a tour of the broad range of subjects they&rsquo;ve explored recording more than 1200 episodes of .NET Rocks over the past 10+ years. After a short break, in which we are hoping to provide some light refreshments, Carl and Richard will be recording a live show with special guest Gary Short.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>ScotNetRocks!</strong></p>

<p>Join Carl Franklin and Richard Campbell as they take you on a tour of the broad range of subjects they’ve explored recording more than 1200 episodes of .NET Rocks! over the past 10+ years. The development world today is evolving rapidly, but a look at the history of development can help inform the path we’re on and where we’re going. Along the way you’ll hear some great stories from the various .NET Rocks! episodes and get some ideas of how you can take your career and your company into the future of technology.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/scotnetrocks-aberdeen-tickets-19517547510?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - ScotNetRocks! Aberdeen" /></a></p>

<p>This will be a three date tour of Scotland, more information and tickets can be found here:
+ <a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/scotnetrocks-glasgow-tickets-19597665144?aff=adnug">Glasgow: 18th January 2016.</a>
+ <a href="http://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/scotnetrocks-edinburgh-tickets-19510803338?aff=adnug">Edinburgh: 19th January 2016.</a>
+ <a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/scotnetrocks-aberdeen-tickets-19517547510?aff=blog">Aberdeen: 21st January 2016.</a></p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday,  21st January 2016</strong>
+ 1815 - Doors open
+ 1825 - Introduction &amp; Housekeeping
+ 1830 - Future of Tech - Carl and Richard
+ 1930 - Break
+ 2000 - .NET Rocks! Live Recording with special guest Gary Short
+ 2100 - Finish</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N242, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Sponsors</strong></p>

<p>Big thanks to our sponsors, whose support and generosity have enabled us to bring you the .NET Rocks! Scottish Tour.</p>

<p>Codify</p>

<p>Founded in 2000, Codify have over a decade of experience developing custom applications for the oil and gas industry used by companies of all sizes, from small local businesses to global corporations. Being based in Aberdeen has allowed Codify to gain a high level of knowledge about the energy industry. Codify love to hire smart people, have happy customers and build software that helps their clients get their job done.
For more information please visit their site at <a href="http://www.codify.ltd.uk/">http://www.codify.ltd.uk/</a></p>

<p>Evoke IT</p>

<p>Evoke IT are Aberdeen’s Microsoft Cloud Specialists and not your ordinary IT company. As a team they design, build and deploy bespoke systems which automate processes, reduce costs and simply improve your work environment. Evoke IT cover the full range of Microsoft Technologies including SharePoint, Office 365 and Azure, providing consultancy, development, training and support. Having recently expanded their offering to include Managed Services, Evoke IT are set to fully support their clients from Infrastructure to Application Development.
For more information please visit their site at <a href="http://www.evokeit.com/">http://www.evokeit.com/</a></p>

<p>Lockheed Martin</p>

<p>Lockheed Martin is a global technology organisation with three key areas of focus in the UK; Transportation &amp; Energy, Public Services and Security &amp; Defence. With over 3,000 people throughout the UK, our team of experts ensure our technology solutions enable customers to overcome challenges and become more efficient. We have a proven history of supporting some of the most complex businesses in the world. Our customers include Scottish Government, Heathrow Airport, the NHS, Total E&amp;P, the Ministry of Justice, NATS and Scottish Power.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[October Meeting - Gary Ewan Park - Completed]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/October-2015-meeting-gary-ewan-park-completed"/>
    <updated>2015-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/October-2015-meeting-gary-ewan-park-completed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks once again to Gary for his talk on GitVersion!  If you want to get in touch with Gary, you can use his twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/gep13">@gep13</a> and make sure you follow him for up-to-date news, articles and tips. You can also find a copy of the slides used in the presentation <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/gep13/semantic-versioning-with-gitversion-take-2">here</a>.  If you have any questions about GitVersion, you can also ask them at the Gitter Chat room, which you can find <a href="https://gitter.im/GitTools/GitVersion">here</a>.</p>

<p><strong> Prizes </strong></p>

<p>For everyone who was lucky enough to win a prize from one of our amazing <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>, I have requested all of the prizes.  If you haven&rsquo;t heard anything, please get in touch, and we will try to sort this out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[October 2015 Meeting - Gary Ewan Park]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/october-2015-meeting-gary-ewan-park"/>
    <updated>2015-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/october-2015-meeting-gary-ewan-park</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Gary Ewan Park, on Thursday 22nd October 2015 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Semantic Versioning with GitVersion</strong></p>

<p>Have you ever needed to control the version number of your application? If so, you will know that this isn’t something that you “get for free”. It’s hard! You may have tried to use some form of auto incrementing number from your Continuous Integration Server, or store a text file in source control and update it each time the build happens. Both of these approaches will work, but they don’t account for more complicated scenarios where you are working on multiple releases at the same time, or you want to use multiple Continuous Integration Servers. In this session, we will look at how we can improve the versioning of your application using a combination of branching strategies (either Gitflow or Githubflow) and an open source tool called GitVersion. GitVersion is a tool which allows you to easy generate the Semantic Version number for your application, based on the current state of your code base in it’s Git Repository.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-october-2015-meeting-tickets-18944026092?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - October 2015 Meeting #1" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong>
Gary Ewan Park has been developing on the .Net Platform for almost 9 years. His day job with Digital Applications Internatational sees him developing using ASP.NET, AngularJS, WPF, SharePoint, Silverlight, and WCF for Oil Companies working in the North Sea.</p>

<p>In his spare time, Gary contributes to a number of Open Source projects including Chocolatey, ChocolateyGUI, Boxstarter, psake-contrib, GitVersion, and GitReleaseManager.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday,  22nd October 2015</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: Semantic Versioning with GitVersion
+ 1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N311, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[September Meeting - Max Vasilyev - Completed]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/September-2015-meeting-max-vasilyev-completed"/>
    <updated>2015-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/September-2015-meeting-max-vasilyev-completed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks once again to Max for coming along to Aberdeen Devlopers to deliver his awesome talk on CQRS!  If you want to get in touch with Max, you can use his twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/trailmax">@trailmax</a> and make sure you follow him for up-to-date news, articles and tips. You can also find a copy of the slides used in the presentation <a href="https://github.com/trailmax/CQRS.Talk">here</a>.</p>

<p><strong> Prizes </strong></p>

<p>For everyone who was lucky enough to win a prize from one of our amazing <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>, the prizes will be requested in due course.  If you don&rsquo;t hear anything, please get in touch, and we will try to sort this out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[September Meeting - Colin Mackay - Completed]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/September-2015-meeting-colin-mackay-completed"/>
    <updated>2015-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/September-2015-meeting-colin-mackay-completed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks once again to Colin for making the journey up to Aberdeen to deliver his awesome talk on Continuous Delivery!  If you want to get in touch with Colin, you can use his twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/colinmackay">@colinmackay</a> and make sure you follow him for up-to-date news, articles and tips. You can also find a copy of the slides used in the presentation <a href="http://colinmackay.scot/2015/09/13/continuous-delivery-aberdeen-developers-net-user-group/">here</a>.</p>

<p><strong> Prizes </strong></p>

<p>For everyone who was lucky enough to win a prize from one of our amazing <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>, I have requested all of the prizes.  If you haven&rsquo;t heard anything, please get in touch, and we will try to sort this out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[August Meeting - Mike Taulty - Completed]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/August-2015-meeting-mike-taulty-completed"/>
    <updated>2015-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/August-2015-meeting-mike-taulty-completed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks once again to Mike for making the journey up to Aberdeen to deliver his awesome talk on Windows 10 and the Universal Windows App Platform!  If you want to get in touch with Mike, you can use his twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/mtaulty">@mtaulty</a> and make sure you follow him for up-to-date news, articles and tips. You can also find a copy of the slides used in the presentation <a href="http://1drv.ms/1NkYYJr">here</a>.</p>

<p><strong> Prizes </strong></p>

<p>For everyone who was lucky enough to win a prize from one of our amazing <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>, I have requested all of the prizes.  If you haven&rsquo;t heard anything, please get in touch, and we will try to sort this out.</p>

<p>As Mike mentioned, there is the possibility of getting some Windows 10 Swag in the form of t-shirts.  I am currently working on this, and once I know more, I will let you know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[September 2015 Meeting #2 - Max Vasilyev]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/september-2015-meeting-2-max-vasilyev"/>
    <updated>2015-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/september-2015-meeting-2-max-vasilyev</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Max Vasilyev, on Thursday 24th September 2015 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Command Query Responsibility Segregation</strong></p>

<p>CQRS (Command Query Responsibility Segregation) have been around for a while and many people called and used this architecture/pattern differently. Probably many of you have read many articles about this approach, but never actually got to do it on practice.</p>

<p>In this session there will be a brief theoretical discussion followed by practical examples with code samples and discussion of benefits of this approach.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-september-2015-meeting-2-tickets-18308807135?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - September 2015 Meeting #2" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong>
Max Vasilyev is a Senior Developer in one of Aberdeen’s .Net development houses. He has been successfully using CQRS in different projects for over 2 years. And he is keen to share his experience with wider audience.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 24th September 2015</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: Command Query Responsibility Segregation
+ 1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N346, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[September 2015 Meeting #1 - Colin Mackay]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/september-2015-meeting-1-colin-mackay"/>
    <updated>2015-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/september-2015-meeting-1-colin-mackay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Colin Mackay, on Thursday 10th September 2015 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Continuous Delivery</strong></p>

<p>Manually delivery software can be a time consuming and error prone affair. Why have a valuable person sit and manually do this? They&rsquo;re bored, and as a result they&rsquo;re not paying full attention and mistakes happen. It isn&rsquo;t repeatable so all those deployments to the testing environment count for nothing when it all goes horribly wrong when deploying to the production environment. There must be a better way of delivering software.</p>

<p>There is!</p>

<p>Amazon reportedly deploys to production every few seconds, GitHub do it several times a day. What makes this possible is a continuous delivery pipeline - a set of processes and a culture of development that ensure that get you to the point where every commit to your source repository is a potential for production system.</p>

<p>Continuous Delivery aims to remove the issues with building, testing and ultimately deploying to production in a safe, repeatable, well tested and highly confident way. I aim to show you how to get started on this journey. It isn&rsquo;t as daunting as it first looks.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-september-2015-meeting-1-tickets-18308101023?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - September 2015 Meeting #1" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong>
Colin Mackay is a software developer, former MVP, and speaker at user groups and previous DDD events.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday,  10th September 2015</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: Continuous Delivery
+ 1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N310, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[August 2015 Meeting #2 - Mike Taulty]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/august-2015-meeting-2-mike-taulty"/>
    <updated>2015-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/august-2015-meeting-2-mike-taulty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Mike Taulty, on Thursday 27th August 2015 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Windows 10 and the Universal Windows App Platform</strong></p>

<p>Windows 10 is a big release for Microsoft. Commodious. Huge. Massive. Colossal. Humongous. ;-)</p>

<p>It’s the end of a journey to unify Windows. It’s the beginning of a journey for developers who want to take advantage of a universal app platform available across all Windows devices.</p>

<p>In this session, we’ll dig into what’s changed in Windows 10 for the Windows app developer. We’ll talk about the Universal App Platform that makes it possible to build code that runs on all Windows devices and about the Extension platforms for code that targets specific device families.</p>

<p>We’ll stay in Visual Studio as much as is possible and we’ll lean towards C# and XAML.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-august-2015-meeting-2-tickets-18094386798?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - August 2015 Meeting #2" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Mike Taulty works in the Developer and Platform Group at Microsoft in the UK where he has spent the past few years helping developers understand and get the best from the Microsoft platform. Prior to this, Mike spent 3 years with Microsoft Consulting Services as a consultant on developer technologies.</p>

<p>Before joining Microsoft, Mike spent the previous 9 years working as a software developer for a number of enterprises, consultancies and software vendors working with a variety of operating system, client, communication and server technologies. You can find more of a complete career history over on <a href="http://uk.linkedin.com/in/mtaulty">LinkedIn</a>.</p>

<p>Mike holds a BSc Hons (1st Class) in Computer Science from the University of Leeds.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 27th August 2015</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: Windows 10 and the Universal Windows App Platform
+ 1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N311, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[August 2015 Meeting #1 - Mark Rendle]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/august-2015-meeting-1-mark-rendle"/>
    <updated>2015-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/august-2015-meeting-1-mark-rendle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Mark Rendle, on Thursday 20th August 2015 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Docker Strangelove - ASP.NET 5 on Linux</strong></p>

<p>Come and learn all about hacking on ASP.NET on Linux!</p>

<p>Linux is now an officially supported platform for ASP.NET applications and you can use epic open-source things like Docker to manage your deployments.</p>

<p>In this session Mark will show us how to run an ASP.NET 5 application on Linux, then in Docker on Linux, and a whole lot more going as far down the rabbit hole as time allows. There may even be time to set up a mini-cloud-within-a-cloud with automated deployments from GitHub!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-august-2015-meeting-tickets-17423409888?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - August 2015 Meeting #1" /></a></p>

<p>WARNING: may contain traces of demo-fail</p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Mark is the founder and CTO of Oort Corporation, a new company building cloud-based software for people who build cloud-based software. Oort&rsquo;s first product, Zudio, a Windows Azure Storage toolkit, is currently in public preview and will be fully launching in April 2013. Mark has been a Windows Azure Development MVP for three years.</p>

<p>In his spare time, Mark work&rsquo;s on the Simple.Data not-an-ORM and Simple.Web projects, and wanders the world speaking at conferences and user groups. Or he just geeks out learning new programming languages and frameworks; in 2013 he&rsquo;s working a lot with TypeScript and AngularJS.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 20th August 2015</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration</li>
<li>1825 - 1830: Introduction</li>
<li>1830 - 1930: Docker Strangelove - ASP.NET 5 on Linux</li>
<li>1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N204, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July Meeting - Matt Ellis - Completed]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/July-2015-meeting-matt-ellis-completed"/>
    <updated>2015-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/July-2015-meeting-matt-ellis-completed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks once again to Matt for making the journey up to Aberdeen to deliver his awesome talk on .Net Core!  If you want to get in touch with Matt, you can use his twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/citizenmatt">@citizenmatt</a> and make sure you follow him for up-to-date news, articles and tips. You can also find a copy of the slides used in the presentation <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/citizenmatt/dot-netcoreblimey-07-2015">here</a>.</p>

<p><strong> Prizes </strong></p>

<p>For everyone who was lucky enough to win a prize from one of our amazing <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>, I have requested all of the prizes.  If you haven&rsquo;t heard anything, please get in touch, and we will try to sort this out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 2015 Meeting - Matt Ellis]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/july-2015-meeting-matt-ellis"/>
    <updated>2015-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/july-2015-meeting-matt-ellis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present the final night of Matt Ellis’s Scottish Tour. Join us on Thursday 23rd July 2015 at the Robert Gordon University to learn more about Microsoft’s recent move to open-source .NET!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>.NETCore Blimey!</strong></p>

<p>Microsoft have done the unthinkable and open-sourced .net, making it available on GitHub, and even taking it cross-platform. This is great news for developers, but do you know your .NET Core from your .Net Framework? Can you tell your CoreCLR from your CoreFX? And where does asp.net vnext and DNX come into this story? In this session, we’ll take a look at the big picture, dive deeply into some of the more interesting details and see how the pieces of Microsoft’s new .Net stack fit together, what it means for developers and find out exactly how you do run an .exe on Unix.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-july-2015-meeting-tickets-17423404873?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - July 2015 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Matt Ellis is a developer at JetBrains, working on the Developer Advocacy team. He has 20 years of experience shipping software, having been a developer, team lead and technical authority for companies such as BBC Worldwide, BNP Paribas and Egg, the UK’s first internet bank. During that time, he has worked with a variety of platforms and technologies, from C++ and Unix to C#, Reactive Extensions and the Web. He currently works with language tooling, having fun with abstract syntax trees and source code analysis. He owns and contributes to various open source projects, and believes in the open closed principle.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 23rd July 2015 </strong></p>

<ul>
<li>1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration</li>
<li>1825 - 1830: Introduction</li>
<li>1830 - 1930: .NETCore Blimey!</li>
<li>1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N204, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.
<strong>Tour Dates</strong></p>

<p>As part of the Scotland Tour, Matt will also be presenting at the following venues:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/c-6-features-and-tooling-tickets-17510913614">Skyscanner, Edinburgh - Tuesday, 21st July</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/net-core-blimey-tickets-17510783224">Skyscanner, Glasgow - Wednesday, 22nd July</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
