<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Job Vacancy | Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/blog/categories/job-vacancy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2016-07-13T15:24:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@aberdeendevelopers.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy - Brightree - Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-brightree-aberdeen"/>
    <updated>2016-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-brightree-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers have been asked to promote the following job vacancy at Brightree. If you are interested in the position, please contact douglas dot cameron at aberdeendevelopers dot co dot uk (replacing the at and dot with @ and . respectively, trying to stop those nasty spiders getting my email address). Details of the job are as follows:</p>

<hr />

<p>Brightree, the fastest growing cloud based business management solution in the U.S. healthcare market, are seeking UK based team-players to join their expanding Aberdeen office.</p>

<p>The ideal candidates have a propensity to share concepts and techniques as well as foster and encourage sharing of knowledge. You will participate in the technical design of the solutions including data modeling, functional design, test criteria, user interface design and development. Practical, relevant experience as a creative problem solver and a proven ability to convert specifications into exception software solutions are critical.</p>

<p><strong>Primary Duties:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Develop new software features</li>
<li>Maintain existing code through defect correction and refactoring</li>
<li>Participate in technical design</li>
<li>DB design/changes</li>
<li>Provide unit tests for all code</li>
<li>Conduct code reviews with other developers</li>
<li>Follow best practices for software development in a cloud based environment</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Basic Qualifications:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Experience working for a software company with web-based applications using Microsoft technologies.</li>
<li>Knowledge of C# or VB.net, ASP.NET and web technologies such as Web API, WCF, JavaScript, CSS, HTML and Ajax.</li>
<li>Experience with MS SQL Server (TSQL/SQL)</li>
<li>OO knowledge and practical experience of design patterns etc</li>
<li>Practical experience with source code configuration, versioning and promotion</li>
<li>Excellent problem solving, issue identification and technical documentation skills</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple concurrent priorities and meeting deadlines</li>
<li>Strong interpersonal and communication skills</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Preferred Requirements:</strong>
- Experience using VS 2015, SQL Server, Xamarin, .net 4.0/4.5 techniques a plus
- Agile software methodology experience a plus
- Experience working in a SaaS model a plus</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy - Software Developer - SPD]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-software-developer-spd"/>
    <updated>2014-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-software-developer-spd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers have been asked to promote the following job vacancy.  If you are interested in the position, or would like some more information, then please use the following link:</p>

<p><a href="https://petrofac.taleo.net/careersection/2/jobdetail.ftl?job=008338&amp;lang=en">https://petrofac.taleo.net/careersection/2/jobdetail.ftl?job=008338&amp;lang=en</a></p>

<hr />


<p><strong>Purpose</strong></p>

<p>WellAtlas is a software tool used internally by our Well Engineering team and also by a number of global operators. It is now a proven solution encompassing a series of integrated specialist modules, that together, bring visibility and assurance of all critical elements required to meet a company’s project delivery agenda. Due to internal and external client requirements as well as our Product Roadmap, the opportunity for a Software Developer has become key to the continued growth of this service line.</p>

<p>The role of the Software Developer will encompass all aspects of the software life cycle from initial requirements gathering through design, build and testing and onto deployment and support.</p>

<p><strong>Role:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Coordination of multiple simultaneous streams of software development between existing and potential clients</li>
<li>Design, development and implementation of both internal and client driven software projects</li>
<li>Collaboration with Product Management by validating the product roadmap, setting priorities and providing estimates</li>
<li>Ensuring visibility through lightweight metrics and continuous project status reporting</li>
<li>Ensure document quality and technical accuracy. Creation and maintenance of development documentation (coding standards etc.)</li>
<li>Design, development and implementation of both internal and client driven software projects</li>
<li>Development of reports using Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services, as well as developing any necessary ASP.NET (C#) web pages and dialogs for selection of reporting criteria, filters etc.</li>
<li>Administration and support of IIS and SQL Servers.</li>
<li>The candidate will be flexible, driven and show a ‘can do’ attitude</li>
</ul>


<p>Please see the link above for full details of &ldquo;Key Accountabilities&rdquo;, &ldquo;Knowledge, Skills &amp; Experience expected&rdquo;, and &ldquo;Minimum Qualifications required&rdquo;</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>Closing Date: 20 October 2014</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy - Web and Applications Developer for RGU - Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-web-applications-developer-rgu-aberdeen"/>
    <updated>2014-03-25T20:56:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-web-applications-developer-rgu-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers have been asked to promote the following job vacancy.  If you are interested in the position, or would like some more information, then please use the following link:</p>

<p><a href="http://www4.rgu.ac.uk/jobs/disp_details_sum.cfm?RJ_ID=41294">http://www4.rgu.ac.uk/jobs/disp_details_sum.cfm?RJ_ID=41294</a></p>

<p><strong>Web and Applications Developer</strong> (Ref C41294)
IT Services Department</p>

<p>We require a Web and Application Developer with experience in the overall architecture, design and support of online applications and a passion for learning and working with leading technologies.</p>

<p>You will be working as part of the in house development team and will have responsibility for the day to day support, administration and development of a wide variety of services and applications.
You&rsquo;ll need significant knowledge and experience of developing applications for the web including understanding of Object Oriented coding concepts and techniques.</p>

<p>We also expect you to have a strong understanding of one or more leading web application technologies such as PHP, ASP.NET, C# or ColdFusion, and associated technologies such as HTML, CSS, Javascript and XML.</p>

<p>We’re in the business of changing lives – developing students into highly employable graduates. Be part of their amazing journey by joining our 1500 colleagues who already enjoy the vibrant community, richly rewarding work, competitive pay and lifestyle afforded by the generous 38 days annual holiday allowance (including statutory holidays).</p>

<p>There are a restricted number of certificates of sponsorship available in the UK and there is no guarantee that the University would be able to obtain one should the successful candidate require one.</p>

<p><strong>Salary: £35085 - £37681 including market supplement</strong></p>

<p>Position Type: Full-time , Permanent</p>

<p>Relocation assistance will be available for this post</p>

<p><strong>Closing Date: 13 April 2014</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy - .Net Developer at BusinessPort - Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-net-developer-businessport-aberdeen"/>
    <updated>2013-12-05T21:11:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-net-developer-businessport-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers have been asked to promote the following job vacancy.  If you are interested in the position, or would like some information, then please contact Douglas Cameron on douglas dot cameron at businessport dot net.</p>

<p>BusinessPort is a specialised provider of web-based Management Systems and services that enable organisations to optimise the interaction between people, process, risk and regulations. Since formation, BusinessPort has assisted companies in all industries to move away from the complexity and inconsistency of paper procedures and delivered proven methodologies and technologies to help them propagate best practice throughout their organisations.</p>

<p>We are looking for an experienced .Net Developer who has a good understanding of the .Net framework and related development tools to join our expanding team. You will have the opportunity to work with some of the latest technologies across a number of platforms as we continue to enhance and develop Agility and associated solutions. Successful candidates should be educated to degree level, have excellent communication skills, be enthusiastic about development and be a natural problem solver. You will be required to work effectively by yourself as well as within a team.</p>

<p>Skills and experience required:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>At least 2 years commercial C# .NET experience.</p></li>
<li><p>WPF and/or Silverlight</p></li>
<li><p>Asp.net (Web forms and/or MVC)</p></li>
<li><p>HTML, CSS and JavaScript</p></li>
<li><p>WCF</p></li>
<li><p>Microsoft SQL Server</p></li>
<li><p>Experience with working with ORMs (ie LINQ to SQL or Entity Framework)</p></li>
<li><p>Familiarly with source control (TFS, Subversion, VSS etc)</p></li>
</ul>


<p>One or more of the following skills would be beneficial:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Office Add in development</p></li>
<li><p>Works with Unit Testing such as NUnit or MSTest</p></li>
<li><p>Experience or an interest in mobile development</p></li>
<li><p>SSIS (SQL Server Integration Services)</p></li>
<li><p>SSRS (SQL Server Reporting Services)</p></li>
<li><p>Installation and deployment tools</p></li>
<li><p>Microsoft Certification</p></li>
<li><p>SharePoint</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy - Senergy Software - Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-senergy-software-aberdeen"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T18:09:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-senergy-software-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers have been asked to promote the following job vacancy. If you are interested in the position, or would like some more information, then please contact <a href="mailto:leanne.burnett@senergyworld.com">Leanne Burnett</a>.  The vacancy is within the Senergy Banchory Office.</p>

<p>Senergy Software was launched as a result of significant business growth within Senergy’s oil and gas division and is supported by the Group’s international locations and technical specialists. The software division develops, markets and supports innovative technologies including Interactive Petrophysics (IP) and Oilfield Data Manager (ODM3) which have become invaluable resource tools for more than 500 Senergy clients globally.</p>

<p><strong>Our Products:</strong></p>

<p>IP (Interactive Petrophysics) is a pioneering analysis tool for petrophysics in that it offers some of the most sophisticated interpretation modules in the industry. Developed by petrophysicists, the portable and versatile technology allows petrophysicists to carry out multi-zone, multi-well field analysis while geologists also use the system.</p>

<p>ODM3 is used in the integration, interpretation and presentation of geological data. This application enables geoscientists to quickly and easily assimilate and visualise numerous data types with the objective of using all available information to make an informed interpretation of the subsurface geology.</p>

<p><strong>Job Specification - Software Developer</strong></p>

<p>As part of our continued expansion Senergy are looking for additional talented people to join our growing software team.</p>

<p>We are currently taking applications for both:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Software Developers</p></li>
<li><p>Talented Students/Graduates</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Candidate Criteria and Skills:</strong></p>

<p>Candidate will possess the drive, enthusiasm and ambition to form part of a dynamic team within a fast-moving company. Candidate needs to be willing to embrace challenge and will have the opportunity to shape their Team.</p>

<p><strong>Your Qualities:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p> Enthusiastic about software development</p></li>
<li><p> Can bring something new to our team</p></li>
<li><p> Happy to learn and share knowledge</p></li>
<li><p> Admit your own strengths and weaknesses</p></li>
<li><p> Loves to learn</p></li>
<li><p> Determined to produce quality software</p></li>
<li><p> Trustworthy and Professional</p></li>
<li><p> We like you already</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Qualifications:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Degree in relevant numerical subject or appropriate skills and experience</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Required Experience:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p> Software Development using either .NET, C#, VB or Java</p></li>
<li><p> Software design experience • Architecture design</p></li>
<li><p> Software quality management • Database and SQL</p></li>
<li><p> Software development life cycle Desirable Experience</p></li>
<li><p> Team Leading / Project Management • Documentation/Presentation skills</p></li>
<li><p> Visual Basic 6 (VB6) or Delphi exposure an advantage but not essential</p></li>
<li><p> Geology or geological background an advantage, but not essential</p></li>
<li><p> Mentoring</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Can you identify your own attributes below?</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p> Degree qualified</p></li>
<li><p> Quality and Technical focus</p></li>
<li><p> Strong mentoring and coaching skills</p></li>
<li><p> Strong communication skills are essential</p></li>
<li><p> Self motivating • Confident • Approachable</p></li>
<li><p> Good networking skills</p></li>
<li><p> Flexible attitude</p></li>
<li><p> Team player</p></li>
<li><p> Strong work ethic</p></li>
<li><p> Consultative style</p></li>
<li><p> Hands-on</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Your career at Senergy Software starts here&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
