<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blog | Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2016-07-13T15:24:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@aberdeendevelopers.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 2016 Meeting - Mike Taulty]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/july-2016-meeting-mike-taulty"/>
    <updated>2016-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/july-2016-meeting-mike-taulty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Mike Taulty, on Thursday 21th July 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>A Platform for More Personal Computing?</strong></p>

<p>Salt and pepper. Fish and chips. Starsky and Hutch. Windows and PC.</p>

<p>Just as Windows became intrinsically linked with personal computing, Microsoft is working to make that just-over-the-horizon leap towards natural interaction and ‘More Personal Computing’ (MPC). It’s already surfacing today in technologies like ‘Cortana’ and ‘Windows Hello’.</p>

<p>In this session, we’ll take a demo-based approach to look at some of the MPC technologies that Windows developers already have available to them in the Universal Windows Platform and some additional technologies out in the cloud under the banner of ‘Microsoft Cognitive Services’</p>

<p>We’ll look at some things with pens, touch, speech, facial recognition, speaker identification and we’ll see what the Windows 10 app platform has to offer developers building modern apps with an ever-more personal touch.</p>

<p>You should expect Visual Studio, C# code and XAML UI and most of the talk will build up an application from scratch adding features as we go along.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-july-2016-meeting-tickets-26418169456?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - July 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Mike Taulty works in the Developer and Platform Group at Microsoft in the UK where he has spent the past few years helping developers understand and get the best from the Microsoft platform. Prior to this, Mike spent 3 years with Microsoft Consulting Services as a consultant on developer technologies.</p>

<p>Before joining Microsoft, Mike spent the previous 9 years working as a software developer for a number of enterprises, consultancies and software vendors working with a variety of operating system, client, communication and server technologies. You can find more of a complete career history over on <a href="http://uk.linkedin.com/in/mtaulty">LinkedIn</a>.</p>

<p>Mike holds a BSc Hons (1st Class) in Computer Science from the University of Leeds.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 21th July 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: A Platform for More Personal Computing?
+ 1930 - 2000: Q&amp;A and Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N309, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy - Brightree - Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-brightree-aberdeen"/>
    <updated>2016-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-brightree-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers have been asked to promote the following job vacancy at Brightree. If you are interested in the position, please contact douglas dot cameron at aberdeendevelopers dot co dot uk (replacing the at and dot with @ and . respectively, trying to stop those nasty spiders getting my email address). Details of the job are as follows:</p>

<hr />

<p>Brightree, the fastest growing cloud based business management solution in the U.S. healthcare market, are seeking UK based team-players to join their expanding Aberdeen office.</p>

<p>The ideal candidates have a propensity to share concepts and techniques as well as foster and encourage sharing of knowledge. You will participate in the technical design of the solutions including data modeling, functional design, test criteria, user interface design and development. Practical, relevant experience as a creative problem solver and a proven ability to convert specifications into exception software solutions are critical.</p>

<p><strong>Primary Duties:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Develop new software features</li>
<li>Maintain existing code through defect correction and refactoring</li>
<li>Participate in technical design</li>
<li>DB design/changes</li>
<li>Provide unit tests for all code</li>
<li>Conduct code reviews with other developers</li>
<li>Follow best practices for software development in a cloud based environment</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Basic Qualifications:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Experience working for a software company with web-based applications using Microsoft technologies.</li>
<li>Knowledge of C# or VB.net, ASP.NET and web technologies such as Web API, WCF, JavaScript, CSS, HTML and Ajax.</li>
<li>Experience with MS SQL Server (TSQL/SQL)</li>
<li>OO knowledge and practical experience of design patterns etc</li>
<li>Practical experience with source code configuration, versioning and promotion</li>
<li>Excellent problem solving, issue identification and technical documentation skills</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple concurrent priorities and meeting deadlines</li>
<li>Strong interpersonal and communication skills</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Preferred Requirements:</strong>
- Experience using VS 2015, SQL Server, Xamarin, .net 4.0/4.5 techniques a plus
- Agile software methodology experience a plus
- Experience working in a SaaS model a plus</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[May 2016 Meeting - Kendall Miller]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/may-2016-meeting-kendall-miller"/>
    <updated>2016-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/may-2016-meeting-kendall-miller</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Kendall Miller, on Thursday 12th May 2016 at Aberdeen University&rsquo;s Meston Building.</p>

<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> Please take extra notice of the venue above!  Due to exams happening in our normal RGU venue, this talk will be being hosted by Aberdeen University, in the Meston Building.  Full details of the location can be found below.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>To The Cloud! How Azure helped us improve the scalability of our SaaS</strong></p>

<p>Last year we had to make a decision whether to double down with new hardware in our Colo or go another way to grow our SaaS. In this talk we&rsquo;ll walk through the challenges we&rsquo;ve faced moving from our own hardware to Azure including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Taking advantage of auto-scaling to reduce costs.</li>
<li>Growing 100x without controlling the hardware.</li>
<li>When it all goes wrong and Azure falls over.</li>
<li>How Azure has improved the performance of our on-premises installs too</li>
</ul>


<p>Far from a theoretical conversation about how you could use the cloud, we&rsquo;ll share real data from our production implementation, both the good and the bad. Finally, we&rsquo;ll talk about where we&rsquo;re going with what we&rsquo;ve learned.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-may-2016-meeting-tickets-24846287916?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - May 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Kendall Miller is one of the founding partners of Gibraltar Software, an Independent Software Vendor (ISV) that develops &amp; markets commercial applications for .NET developers. Introduced commercially in 2009, Loupe is an application logging &amp; monitoring platform that is currently used by customers around the world from individual consultants through Fortune 100 companies and governments. Before starting Gibraltar Software, Kendall worked for multiple startups leading their technology development from beginning through profitability. In each case he&rsquo;s focused on translating enterprise-level performance and capabilities down to smaller companies. Kendall has a B.S in Computer Engineering from the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 12th May 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: To The Cloud! How Azure helped us improve the scalability of our SaaS
+ 1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Meston Building (Enter via North Entrance), University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, AB24 3UE</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/viewer?mid=zy5sr2VnGJ2w.khFsoArRBh_Y&amp;hl=en">Meston Building</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[April 2016 Meeting - Gary Ewan Park]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/april-2016-meeting-gary-ewan-park"/>
    <updated>2016-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/april-2016-meeting-gary-ewan-park</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Gary Ewan Park, on Thursday 21st April 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Having your Cake, and eating to too!</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script for your application, but been faced with learning a new language, or DSL, or writing more XML than any person should ever need to?</li>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script that will work cross platform?</li>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script that has first class support for the most common build tools like XUnit, WiX, SignTool, and many others?</li>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script that uses a language that you already know, and love?</li>
</ul>


<p>If you have answered yes to any of these questions, then the Cake (<a href="http://cakebuild.net/">http://cakebuild.net/</a>) Build Automation System is for you!</p>

<p>In this session we will start with a standard .Net Solution and incrementally add a build and orchestration script to compile the application, run unit tests, perform static analysis, package the application, and more, using the C# skills that you may already have.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-april-2016-meeting-tickets-24528759179?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - April 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong>
Gary Ewan Park has been developing on the .Net Platform for almost 9 years. His day job sees him developing using ASP.NET, AngularJS, and WPF, for Oil Companies working in the North Sea.</p>

<p>In his spare time, Gary contributes to a number of Open Source projects including Chocolatey, Boxstarter, Cake, psake and GitVersion.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday,  21st April 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: Having your Cake, and eating to too!
+ 1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N309, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[March 2016 Meeting - Christos Matskas]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2016-meeting-christos-matskas"/>
    <updated>2016-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2016-meeting-christos-matskas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Christos Matskas, on Thursday 24th March 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Microsoft’s ASP.NET Core 1.0 is going to rock your world</strong></p>

<p>ASP.NET Core has been rewritten from the ground up to be the best web development platform for Windows, Mac, and Linux. You can now use your favorite editor to create faster, leaner and more memory efficient ASP.NET applications that work everywhere. In this session, you&rsquo;ll get an introduction to the major advancements and an overview of what&rsquo;s changed and what&rsquo;s stayed the same. You&rsquo;ll also get the chance to see how you can leverage all the new front-end tooling like npm, Bower, Grunt and Gulp to manage your application. This is going to be session full of demos and information that promises to rock your world!</p>

<p>In addition, Christos will be presented a bonus lightning talk entitled:</p>

<p><strong>Becoming an awesome Open Source contributor</strong></p>

<p>Are you a developer that wants to give back to the open source community? Perhaps you&rsquo;re already a seasoned contributor but you want to get better? Or you want to join the open source movement because, well, OSS is the future? Just look at all the cool tech built with OSS: Node.js, BootStrap, ASP.NET etc. Join Christos Matskas to learn about the many ways to contribute, key development tools in OSS projects and tips about what it takes to become a succesful first time contributor and collaborator in this welcoming and open community.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-march-2016-meeting-tickets-21670650499?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=21670650499" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - March 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Christos Matskas is a software consultant, author, blogger and speaker. A Microsoft MVP on Visual Studio and Development Technologies, he&rsquo;s a passionate Open Source advocate and a regular contributor to numerous projects. His portfolio includes collaborations with some of the biggest companies in the industry such as MarkIT, Lockheed Martin and Barclays. He&rsquo;s been building software for over 12 years and loves to work closely with the community through speaking at conferences, mentoring and teaching programs.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday,  24th March 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: Microsoft’s ASP.NET Core 1.0 is going to rock your world.
+ 1930 - 1945: Bonus Lightning Talk - Becoming an awesome Open Source contributor
+ 1945 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N309, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
