<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blog | Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-26T20:38:26+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@aberdeendevelopers.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[May 2016 Meeting - Kendall Miller]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/may-2016-meeting-kendall-miller"/>
    <updated>2016-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/may-2016-meeting-kendall-miller</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Kendall Miller, on Thursday 12th May 2016 at Aberdeen University&rsquo;s Meston Building.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>To The Cloud! How Azure helped us improve the scalability of our SaaS</strong></p>

<p>Last year we had to make a decision whether to double down with new hardware in our Colo or go another way to grow our SaaS. In this talk we&rsquo;ll walk through the challenges we&rsquo;ve faced moving from our own hardware to Azure including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Taking advantage of auto-scaling to reduce costs.</li>
<li>Growing 100x without controlling the hardware.</li>
<li>When it all goes wrong and Azure falls over.</li>
<li>How Azure has improved the performance of our on-premises installs too</li>
</ul>


<p>Far from a theoretical conversation about how you could use the cloud, we&rsquo;ll share real data from our production implementation, both the good and the bad. Finally, we&rsquo;ll talk about where we&rsquo;re going with what we&rsquo;ve learned.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-may-2016-meeting-tickets-24846287916?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - May 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Kendall Miller is one of the founding partners of Gibraltar Software, an Independent Software Vendor (ISV) that develops &amp; markets commercial applications for .NET developers. Introduced commercially in 2009, Loupe is an application logging &amp; monitoring platform that is currently used by customers around the world from individual consultants through Fortune 100 companies and governments. Before starting Gibraltar Software, Kendall worked for multiple startups leading their technology development from beginning through profitability. In each case he&rsquo;s focused on translating enterprise-level performance and capabilities down to smaller companies. Kendall has a B.S in Computer Engineering from the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 12th May 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: To The Cloud! How Azure helped us improve the scalability of our SaaS
+ 1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Meston Building (Enter via North Entrance), University of Aberdeen, Aberdeen, AB24 3UE</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/viewer?mid=zy5sr2VnGJ2w.khFsoArRBh_Y&amp;hl=en">Meston Building</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[April 2016 Meeting - Gary Ewan Park]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/april-2016-meeting-gary-ewan-park"/>
    <updated>2016-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/april-2016-meeting-gary-ewan-park</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Gary Ewan Park, on Thursday 21st April 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Having your Cake, and eating to too!</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script for your application, but been faced with learning a new language, or DSL, or writing more XML than any person should ever need to?</li>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script that will work cross platform?</li>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script that has first class support for the most common build tools like XUnit, WiX, SignTool, and many others?</li>
<li>Have you ever wanted to create a build script that uses a language that you already know, and love?</li>
</ul>


<p>If you have answered yes to any of these questions, then the Cake (<a href="http://cakebuild.net/">http://cakebuild.net/</a>) Build Automation System is for you!</p>

<p>In this session we will start with a standard .Net Solution and incrementally add a build and orchestration script to compile the application, run unit tests, perform static analysis, package the application, and more, using the C# skills that you may already have.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-april-2016-meeting-tickets-24528759179?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - April 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong>
Gary Ewan Park has been developing on the .Net Platform for almost 9 years. His day job sees him developing using ASP.NET, AngularJS, and WPF, for Oil Companies working in the North Sea.</p>

<p>In his spare time, Gary contributes to a number of Open Source projects including Chocolatey, Boxstarter, Cake, psake and GitVersion.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday,  21st April 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: Having your Cake, and eating to too!
+ 1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N309, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[March 2016 Meeting - Christos Matskas]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2016-meeting-christos-matskas"/>
    <updated>2016-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2016-meeting-christos-matskas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Christos Matskas, on Thursday 24th March 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Microsoft’s ASP.NET Core 1.0 is going to rock your world</strong></p>

<p>ASP.NET Core has been rewritten from the ground up to be the best web development platform for Windows, Mac, and Linux. You can now use your favorite editor to create faster, leaner and more memory efficient ASP.NET applications that work everywhere. In this session, you&rsquo;ll get an introduction to the major advancements and an overview of what&rsquo;s changed and what&rsquo;s stayed the same. You&rsquo;ll also get the chance to see how you can leverage all the new front-end tooling like npm, Bower, Grunt and Gulp to manage your application. This is going to be session full of demos and information that promises to rock your world!</p>

<p>In addition, Christos will be presented a bonus lightning talk entitled:</p>

<p><strong>Becoming an awesome Open Source contributor</strong></p>

<p>Are you a developer that wants to give back to the open source community? Perhaps you&rsquo;re already a seasoned contributor but you want to get better? Or you want to join the open source movement because, well, OSS is the future? Just look at all the cool tech built with OSS: Node.js, BootStrap, ASP.NET etc. Join Christos Matskas to learn about the many ways to contribute, key development tools in OSS projects and tips about what it takes to become a succesful first time contributor and collaborator in this welcoming and open community.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-march-2016-meeting-tickets-21670650499?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=21670650499" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - March 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Christos Matskas is a software consultant, author, blogger and speaker. A Microsoft MVP on Visual Studio and Development Technologies, he&rsquo;s a passionate Open Source advocate and a regular contributor to numerous projects. His portfolio includes collaborations with some of the biggest companies in the industry such as MarkIT, Lockheed Martin and Barclays. He&rsquo;s been building software for over 12 years and loves to work closely with the community through speaking at conferences, mentoring and teaching programs.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday,  24th March 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: Microsoft’s ASP.NET Core 1.0 is going to rock your world.
+ 1930 - 1945: Bonus Lightning Talk - Becoming an awesome Open Source contributor
+ 1945 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N309, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ScotNetRocks! Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/scotnetrocks-aberdeen"/>
    <updated>2016-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/scotnetrocks-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present the final night of the ScotNetRocks! tour, hopefully you’ll be able to join us to hear Carl and Richard kick off the evening as they take us on a tour of the broad range of subjects they&rsquo;ve explored recording more than 1200 episodes of .NET Rocks over the past 10+ years. After a short break, in which we are hoping to provide some light refreshments, Carl and Richard will be recording a live show with special guest Gary Short.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>ScotNetRocks!</strong></p>

<p>Join Carl Franklin and Richard Campbell as they take you on a tour of the broad range of subjects they’ve explored recording more than 1200 episodes of .NET Rocks! over the past 10+ years. The development world today is evolving rapidly, but a look at the history of development can help inform the path we’re on and where we’re going. Along the way you’ll hear some great stories from the various .NET Rocks! episodes and get some ideas of how you can take your career and your company into the future of technology.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/scotnetrocks-aberdeen-tickets-19517547510?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - ScotNetRocks! Aberdeen" /></a></p>

<p>This will be a three date tour of Scotland, more information and tickets can be found here:
+ <a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/scotnetrocks-glasgow-tickets-19597665144?aff=adnug">Glasgow: 18th January 2016.</a>
+ <a href="http://www.eventbrite.co.uk/e/scotnetrocks-edinburgh-tickets-19510803338?aff=adnug">Edinburgh: 19th January 2016.</a>
+ <a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/scotnetrocks-aberdeen-tickets-19517547510?aff=blog">Aberdeen: 21st January 2016.</a></p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday,  21st January 2016</strong>
+ 1815 - Doors open
+ 1825 - Introduction &amp; Housekeeping
+ 1830 - Future of Tech - Carl and Richard
+ 1930 - Break
+ 2000 - .NET Rocks! Live Recording with special guest Gary Short
+ 2100 - Finish</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N242, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Sponsors</strong></p>

<p>Big thanks to our sponsors, whose support and generosity have enabled us to bring you the .NET Rocks! Scottish Tour.</p>

<p>Codify</p>

<p>Founded in 2000, Codify have over a decade of experience developing custom applications for the oil and gas industry used by companies of all sizes, from small local businesses to global corporations. Being based in Aberdeen has allowed Codify to gain a high level of knowledge about the energy industry. Codify love to hire smart people, have happy customers and build software that helps their clients get their job done.
For more information please visit their site at <a href="http://www.codify.ltd.uk/">http://www.codify.ltd.uk/</a></p>

<p>Evoke IT</p>

<p>Evoke IT are Aberdeen’s Microsoft Cloud Specialists and not your ordinary IT company. As a team they design, build and deploy bespoke systems which automate processes, reduce costs and simply improve your work environment. Evoke IT cover the full range of Microsoft Technologies including SharePoint, Office 365 and Azure, providing consultancy, development, training and support. Having recently expanded their offering to include Managed Services, Evoke IT are set to fully support their clients from Infrastructure to Application Development.
For more information please visit their site at <a href="http://www.evokeit.com/">http://www.evokeit.com/</a></p>

<p>Lockheed Martin</p>

<p>Lockheed Martin is a global technology organisation with three key areas of focus in the UK; Transportation &amp; Energy, Public Services and Security &amp; Defence. With over 3,000 people throughout the UK, our team of experts ensure our technology solutions enable customers to overcome challenges and become more efficient. We have a proven history of supporting some of the most complex businesses in the world. Our customers include Scottish Government, Heathrow Airport, the NHS, Total E&amp;P, the Ministry of Justice, NATS and Scottish Power.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[October Meeting - Gary Ewan Park - Completed]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/October-2015-meeting-gary-ewan-park-completed"/>
    <updated>2015-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/October-2015-meeting-gary-ewan-park-completed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks once again to Gary for his talk on GitVersion!  If you want to get in touch with Gary, you can use his twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/gep13">@gep13</a> and make sure you follow him for up-to-date news, articles and tips. You can also find a copy of the slides used in the presentation <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/gep13/semantic-versioning-with-gitversion-take-2">here</a>.  If you have any questions about GitVersion, you can also ask them at the Gitter Chat room, which you can find <a href="https://gitter.im/GitTools/GitVersion">here</a>.</p>

<p><strong> Prizes </strong></p>

<p>For everyone who was lucky enough to win a prize from one of our amazing <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>, I have requested all of the prizes.  If you haven&rsquo;t heard anything, please get in touch, and we will try to sort this out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
