<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blog | Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-15T08:08:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@aberdeendevelopers.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft UK Edinburgh Events]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/microsoft-uk-edinburgh-events"/>
    <updated>2015-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/microsoft-uk-edinburgh-events</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft UK are running a couple of one day events in Edinburgh this month (April), these events offer hands-on sessions guided by experts and are a great place to start with the basics and an opportunity to pick the brains of the experts.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://msevents.microsoft.com/CUI/EventDetail.aspx?EventID=1032622343&amp;Culture=en-GB&amp;community=0">Microsoft Azure Developer Cloud Camp</a></strong></p>

<p>A one-day Azure hands-on camp to experience the versatility of the Azure platform, and see the practical capabilities that Azure brings within reach your business, IT company and department.</p>

<p>22 April 2015 - Edinburgh, 09:00 - 17:00 -
<a href="https://msevents.microsoft.com/CUI/EventDetail.aspx?EventID=1032622343&amp;Culture=en-GB&amp;community=0">Register</a></p>

<p><strong><a href="https://msevents.microsoft.com/CUI/EventDetail.aspx?EventID=1032622342&amp;Culture=en-GB&amp;community=0">Microsoft Developer Web Camp</a></strong></p>

<p>Web Camps are live, no-fluff events created for web developers, by web developers. You’ll learn from seasoned experts who start with the basics and ramp up to more advanced topics as the day goes on. Don&rsquo;t miss this free opportunity to sharpen your web development skills.</p>

<p>23 April 2015 - Edinburgh, 09:00 - 17:00 -
<a href="https://msevents.microsoft.com/CUI/EventDetail.aspx?EventID=1032622342&amp;Culture=en-GB&amp;community=0">Register</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[March 2015 Meeting - Sebastien Lambla]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2015-meeting-sebastien-lambla"/>
    <updated>2015-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2015-meeting-sebastien-lambla</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Sebastien Lambla, on Thursday 12th March 2015 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>OWIN, Why, What and How?</strong></p>

<p>OWIN is a set of open interfaces for web components on .net. Much has changed since the early days of that specification. What is OWIN? What does componentising mean for building web application? Expect to see code, slides, unicorns, Funcs and discussions about how to build your components now and be ready for asp.net vNext for free!</p>

<p><a href="http://adnuguk-march-2015.eventbrite.com/?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - March 2015 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Sebastien Lambla has been involved in software development since receiving his first web browser, back in the days of Netsape Navigator 1.2. After a few years of hacking on javascript, he turned his attention to the .net platform, on which he would spend the next few years building software in many companies. From 2006, Sebastien has been running Caffeine IT, a consultancy helping clients from all over Europe implement first-grade and innovative solutions. Keen Open-Source promoter, Sebastien has created multiple high-profile open-source projects that are in use in many Fortune 500 companies, including OpenRasta, at a time the most popular resource-oriented framework on .net. Long-time advocate of the ReST architectural style and resource-oriented computing, Sebastien has delivered over the years new platforms leveraging the architecture of the web, from small independents to Fortune 500s.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 12th March 2015 </strong></p>

<p>1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
1825 - 1830: Introduction
1830 - 1930: OWIN, Why, What and How?
1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N311, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[February Meeting - Christos Matskas - Completed]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/february-meeting-christos-matskas-completed"/>
    <updated>2015-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/february-meeting-christos-matskas-completed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks once again to Christos for making the journey up to Aberdeen to deliver his awesome talk on Cross platform mobile development with the power of Xamarin! Christos has provided a in depth review his trip along with his slides and the videos captured by himself and BCS Aberdeen, you can find his blog post <a href="https://cmatskas.com/cross-platform-application-development-with-xamarin/">here</a>.  If you want to get in touch with Christos, you can use his twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/christosmatskas">@christosmatskas</a> and make sure you follow him for up-to-date news, articles and tips..</p>

<p><strong> Prizes </strong></p>

<p>For everyone who was lucky enough to win a prize from one of our amazing <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>, I have requested all of the prizes.  If you haven&rsquo;t heard anything, please get in touch, and we will try to sort this out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[February 2015 Meeting - Christos Matskas]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/february-2015-meeting-christos-matskas"/>
    <updated>2015-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/february-2015-meeting-christos-matskas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Christos Matskas, this is a joint event with BCS Aberdeen Branch on Thursday 19th February 2015 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Cross platform mobile development with the power of Xamarin</strong></p>

<p>Are you a .NET developer? Do you develop for mobile platforms or would you like to get started but you don’t know how or where? Then you should join Christos Matskas as he shows you how to get off the ground with mobile application development using the power of Xamarin and explains how to build powerful, full-featured, native applications that can run across all platforms. You will learn how to speed up your development cycle, reduce overhead costs and create “the one codebase to rule them all”.</p>

<p><a href="http://adnuguk-feb2015.eventbrite.com/?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - February 2015 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Christos Matskas has been working as a software developer professionally for the last 11 years. He is the founder and CEO of SoftwareLounge, a software consultancy firm, and co-founder of TowzieTyke an apps development powerhouse. His portfolio includes collaborations with some great companies such as MarkIT, Lockheed Martin and Barclays. Over the years he had the opportunity to work on a numerous exciting projects from mobile apps to data crunching back-end solutions. His blog, <a href="https://cmatskas.com">https://cmatskas.com</a>, is full with useful tutorials, tips and tricks and reviews about software development and tools. Christos also contributes to Open Source and is a regular speaker at conferences and user groups talking about .NET, the Cloud and software development in general.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy - Software Developer - SPD]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-software-developer-spd"/>
    <updated>2014-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-software-developer-spd</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers have been asked to promote the following job vacancy.  If you are interested in the position, or would like some more information, then please use the following link:</p>

<p><a href="https://petrofac.taleo.net/careersection/2/jobdetail.ftl?job=008338&amp;lang=en">https://petrofac.taleo.net/careersection/2/jobdetail.ftl?job=008338&amp;lang=en</a></p>

<hr />


<p><strong>Purpose</strong></p>

<p>WellAtlas is a software tool used internally by our Well Engineering team and also by a number of global operators. It is now a proven solution encompassing a series of integrated specialist modules, that together, bring visibility and assurance of all critical elements required to meet a company’s project delivery agenda. Due to internal and external client requirements as well as our Product Roadmap, the opportunity for a Software Developer has become key to the continued growth of this service line.</p>

<p>The role of the Software Developer will encompass all aspects of the software life cycle from initial requirements gathering through design, build and testing and onto deployment and support.</p>

<p><strong>Role:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Coordination of multiple simultaneous streams of software development between existing and potential clients</li>
<li>Design, development and implementation of both internal and client driven software projects</li>
<li>Collaboration with Product Management by validating the product roadmap, setting priorities and providing estimates</li>
<li>Ensuring visibility through lightweight metrics and continuous project status reporting</li>
<li>Ensure document quality and technical accuracy. Creation and maintenance of development documentation (coding standards etc.)</li>
<li>Design, development and implementation of both internal and client driven software projects</li>
<li>Development of reports using Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services, as well as developing any necessary ASP.NET (C#) web pages and dialogs for selection of reporting criteria, filters etc.</li>
<li>Administration and support of IIS and SQL Servers.</li>
<li>The candidate will be flexible, driven and show a ‘can do’ attitude</li>
</ul>


<p>Please see the link above for full details of &ldquo;Key Accountabilities&rdquo;, &ldquo;Knowledge, Skills &amp; Experience expected&rdquo;, and &ldquo;Minimum Qualifications required&rdquo;</p>

<hr />


<p><strong>Closing Date: 20 October 2014</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
