<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blog | Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-09T18:09:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@aberdeendevelopers.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[October 2016 Meeting - Keith Davidson]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/october-2016-meeting-keith-davidson"/>
    <updated>2016-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/october-2016-meeting-keith-davidson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Keith Davidson, on Thursday 20th October 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>BreezeJS</strong></p>

<p>BreezeJS is a free, open source JavaScript library that helps you manage data in rich client applications. If you store data in a database, query and save those data as complex object graphs, and share these graphs across multiple screens of your JavaScript client, Breeze is for you. This presentation will introduce BreezeJs and demonstrate some of it&rsquo;s advantages.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-october-2016-meeting-tickets-28505462606?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - October 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Keith Davidson has been programming web sites and apps since the late 90&rsquo;s and started his professional development career in 2000, writing applications with consulting firm Accenture.  He is currently a Senior Software Developer with Petrofac.  When not trying to keep up with the latest web technologies or contributing to open source projects, he enjoys tinkering with Raspberry Pi and Arduino platforms and occasionally plays the drums.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 20th October 2016</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration</li>
<li>1825 - 1830: Introduction</li>
<li>1830 - 1930: BreezeJS</li>
<li>1930 - 2000: Q&amp;A and Prize Draw</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N311, The Sir Ian Wood Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7GJ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/The+Sir+Ian+Wood+Building,+Garthdee+Rd,+Aberdeen+AB10+7GJ">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[September 2016 Meeting - Colin Mackay]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/september-2016-meeting-colin-mackay"/>
    <updated>2016-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/september-2016-meeting-colin-mackay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Colin Mackay, on Thursday 15th September 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Storymapping for Beginners</strong></p>

<p>Sometimes it is difficult to work out how to prioritise the backlog and effectively work iteratively while still holding on to the big picture. What do you put in your MVP (Minimal Viable Product)? What then goes in each incremental release to give your users more and more useful functionality? Storymapping is a technique for solving this problem and getting your solution to your users faster.</p>

<p>In this highly interactive session I&rsquo;ll explain how you go about creating a story map and I&rsquo;ll get you to create one. Lots of sticky notes later you should have a fairly good grasp and be able to use the same technique on your own projects to better manage your backlog and keep everyone aware of the big picture while still working on individual stories.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-september-2016-meeting-tickets-27403321071?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - September 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Colin Mackay was C# MVP for 4 years (2007, 2008, 2009, 2010), and Code Project MVP (for 5 years) and, as of writing, is in the top 3% of StackOverflow users. He runs Scottish Developers and organises DDD Scotland.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 15th September 2016</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration</li>
<li>1825 - 1830: Introduction</li>
<li>1830 - 1930: Storymapping for Beginners</li>
<li>1930 - 2000: Q&amp;A and Prize Draw</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N310, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Job Vacancy - Brightree - Aberdeen]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-brightree-aberdeen"/>
    <updated>2016-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/job-vacancy-brightree-aberdeen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers have been asked to promote the following job vacancy at Brightree in Aberdeen. If you are interested in the position, please contact douglas dot cameron at aberdeendevelopers dot co dot uk (replacing the at and dot with @ and . respectively, trying to stop those nasty spiders getting my email address). Details of the role are as follows:</p>

<hr />

<p>Brightree, the fastest growing cloud based business management solution in the U.S. healthcare market, are seeking UK based team-players to join their expanding Aberdeen office.</p>

<p>The ideal candidates have a propensity to share concepts and techniques as well as foster and encourage sharing of knowledge. You will participate in the technical design of the solutions including data modeling, functional design, test criteria, user interface design and development. Practical, relevant experience as a creative problem solver and a proven ability to convert specifications into exception software solutions are critical.</p>

<p><strong>Primary Duties:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Develop new software features</li>
<li>Maintain existing code through defect correction and refactoring</li>
<li>Participate in technical design</li>
<li>DB design/changes</li>
<li>Provide unit tests for all code</li>
<li>Conduct code reviews with other developers</li>
<li>Follow best practices for software development in a cloud based environment</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Basic Qualifications:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Experience working for a software company with web-based applications using Microsoft technologies.</li>
<li>Knowledge of C# or VB.net, ASP.NET and web technologies such as Web API, WCF, JavaScript, CSS, HTML and Ajax.</li>
<li>Experience with MS SQL Server (TSQL/SQL)</li>
<li>OO knowledge and practical experience of design patterns etc</li>
<li>Practical experience with source code configuration, versioning and promotion</li>
<li>Excellent problem solving, issue identification and technical documentation skills</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple concurrent priorities and meeting deadlines</li>
<li>Strong interpersonal and communication skills</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Preferred Requirements:</strong>
- Experience using VS 2015, SQL Server, Xamarin, .net 4.0/4.5 techniques a plus
- Agile software methodology experience a plus
- Experience working in a SaaS model a plus</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[August 2016 Meeting - Steven Chalmers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/august-2016-meeting-steven-chalmers"/>
    <updated>2016-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/august-2016-meeting-steven-chalmers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Steven Chalmers, on Thursday 18th August 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Experiences of using an Azure website and database in Production</strong></p>

<p>Having developed an Azure website for an internal company tool that is used daily by 30 people across multiple sites, I will cover my experiences of using Azure for over a year.</p>

<p>I will share:</p>

<ul>
<li>Reasons why</li>
<li>Setup and running costs</li>
<li>Features and tools of the Azure websites and Azure Databases</li>
<li>Performance, architecture and coding worries and solutions</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-august-2016-meeting-tickets-26706378497?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - August 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Steven Chalmers has been programming on many different computers and embedded systems since the late 70&rsquo;s. From typing in bytes, assembly all the way through to c#. Currently using ASP.NET MVC, Telerik tools on Azure at work but at home its having fun with his kids by game programming in Roblox.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 18th August 2016</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration</li>
<li>1825 - 1830: Introduction</li>
<li>1830 - 1930: Experiences of using an Azure website and database in Production</li>
<li>1930 - 2000: Q&amp;A and Prize Draw</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N310, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 2016 Meeting - Mike Taulty]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/july-2016-meeting-mike-taulty"/>
    <updated>2016-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/july-2016-meeting-mike-taulty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Mike Taulty, on Thursday 21th July 2016 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>A Platform for More Personal Computing?</strong></p>

<p>Salt and pepper. Fish and chips. Starsky and Hutch. Windows and PC.</p>

<p>Just as Windows became intrinsically linked with personal computing, Microsoft is working to make that just-over-the-horizon leap towards natural interaction and ‘More Personal Computing’ (MPC). It’s already surfacing today in technologies like ‘Cortana’ and ‘Windows Hello’.</p>

<p>In this session, we’ll take a demo-based approach to look at some of the MPC technologies that Windows developers already have available to them in the Universal Windows Platform and some additional technologies out in the cloud under the banner of ‘Microsoft Cognitive Services’</p>

<p>We’ll look at some things with pens, touch, speech, facial recognition, speaker identification and we’ll see what the Windows 10 app platform has to offer developers building modern apps with an ever-more personal touch.</p>

<p>You should expect Visual Studio, C# code and XAML UI and most of the talk will build up an application from scratch adding features as we go along.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-july-2016-meeting-tickets-26418169456?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - July 2016 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Mike Taulty works in the Developer and Platform Group at Microsoft in the UK where he has spent the past few years helping developers understand and get the best from the Microsoft platform. Prior to this, Mike spent 3 years with Microsoft Consulting Services as a consultant on developer technologies.</p>

<p>Before joining Microsoft, Mike spent the previous 9 years working as a software developer for a number of enterprises, consultancies and software vendors working with a variety of operating system, client, communication and server technologies. You can find more of a complete career history over on <a href="http://uk.linkedin.com/in/mtaulty">LinkedIn</a>.</p>

<p>Mike holds a BSc Hons (1st Class) in Computer Science from the University of Leeds.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 21th July 2016</strong>
+ 1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
+ 1825 - 1830: Introduction
+ 1830 - 1930: A Platform for More Personal Computing?
+ 1930 - 2000: Q&amp;A and Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N309, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
