<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Events | Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/blog/categories/events/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-19T13:19:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[gep13]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gep13@aberdeendevelopers.co.uk]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[March 2015 Meeting - Sebastien Lambla]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2015-meeting-sebastien-lambla"/>
    <updated>2015-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/march-2015-meeting-sebastien-lambla</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Sebastien Lambla, on Thursday 12th March 2015 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>OWIN, Why, What and How?</strong></p>

<p>OWIN is a set of open interfaces for web components on .net. Much has changed since the early days of that specification. What is OWIN? What does componentising mean for building web application? Expect to see code, slides, unicorns, Funcs and discussions about how to build your components now and be ready for asp.net vNext for free!</p>

<p><a href="http://adnuguk-march-2015.eventbrite.com/?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - March 2015 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Sebastien Lambla has been involved in software development since receiving his first web browser, back in the days of Netsape Navigator 1.2. After a few years of hacking on javascript, he turned his attention to the .net platform, on which he would spend the next few years building software in many companies. From 2006, Sebastien has been running Caffeine IT, a consultancy helping clients from all over Europe implement first-grade and innovative solutions. Keen Open-Source promoter, Sebastien has created multiple high-profile open-source projects that are in use in many Fortune 500 companies, including OpenRasta, at a time the most popular resource-oriented framework on .net. Long-time advocate of the ReST architectural style and resource-oriented computing, Sebastien has delivered over the years new platforms leveraging the architecture of the web, from small independents to Fortune 500s.</p>

<p><strong>Agenda - Thursday, 12th March 2015 </strong></p>

<p>1800 - 1825: Arrival and registration
1825 - 1830: Introduction
1830 - 1930: OWIN, Why, What and How?
1930 Onwards: Questions &amp; Answers followed by Prize Draw</p>

<p><strong>Location and Directions</strong></p>

<p>Venue: Room N311, Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<p><strong>Prize Draw</strong></p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes from our fantastic <a href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/sponsors/">sponsors</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[February 2015 Meeting - Christos Matskas]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/february-2015-meeting-christos-matskas"/>
    <updated>2015-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/february-2015-meeting-christos-matskas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Christos Matskas, this is a joint event with BCS Aberdeen Branch on Thursday 19th February 2015 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Cross platform mobile development with the power of Xamarin</strong></p>

<p>Are you a .NET developer? Do you develop for mobile platforms or would you like to get started but you don’t know how or where? Then you should join Christos Matskas as he shows you how to get off the ground with mobile application development using the power of Xamarin and explains how to build powerful, full-featured, native applications that can run across all platforms. You will learn how to speed up your development cycle, reduce overhead costs and create “the one codebase to rule them all”.</p>

<p><a href="http://adnuguk-feb2015.eventbrite.com/?aff=blog"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - February 2015 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Speaker Bio</strong></p>

<p>Christos Matskas has been working as a software developer professionally for the last 11 years. He is the founder and CEO of SoftwareLounge, a software consultancy firm, and co-founder of TowzieTyke an apps development powerhouse. His portfolio includes collaborations with some great companies such as MarkIT, Lockheed Martin and Barclays. Over the years he had the opportunity to work on a numerous exciting projects from mobile apps to data crunching back-end solutions. His blog, <a href="https://cmatskas.com">https://cmatskas.com</a>, is full with useful tutorials, tips and tricks and reviews about software development and tools. Christos also contributes to Open Source and is a regular speaker at conferences and user groups talking about .NET, the Cloud and software development in general.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[August 2014 Meeting - Shawn Wildermuth]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/august-2014-meeting-shawn-wildermuth"/>
    <updated>2014-06-21T19:42:33+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/august-2014-meeting-shawn-wildermuth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Shawn Wildermuth on Thursday 7th August 2014 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p>Getting started with Web API 2</p>

<p>Are you getting ready to build an API that works over HTTP? ASP.NET Web API 2 is probably your best way to do it. In this talk, Shawn Wildermuth can show you how to create your own API!nit or no unit test?</p>

<p><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-august-2014-meeting-tickets-11987778769?ref=ebtnebregn"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987778769" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - August 2014 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p>Speaker Bio</p>

<p>Shawn Wildermuth is an eight-time Microsoft MVP (Data), member of the INETA Speaker&rsquo;s Bureau and an author of six books and dozens of articles on .NET. Shawn is involved with Microsoft as a Silverlight Insider, Data Insider and Connected Technology Advisors (WCF/Oslo/WF). He has been seen speaking at a variety of international conferences including TechEd, Oredev, SDC, VSLive, WinDev, MIX, DevTeach and DevReach. He is currently teaching workshops around the country through his training company AgiliTrain (<a href="http://agilitrain.com">http://agilitrain.com</a>). He can also be reached via his blog at <a href="http://wildermuth.com/">http://wildermuth.com</a>.</p>

<hr />

<p>Agenda - Thursday, 7th August 2014</p>

<ul>
<li><p>1800 - 1815: Arrival and registration</p></li>
<li><p>1815 - 1820: Introduction</p></li>
<li><p>1820 - 1920: Getting started with Web API 2</p></li>
<li><p>1920 onwards: Questions and drinks at the bar</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Prize Draw</p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes listed <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=107">here</a>.</p>

<p>Location and Directions</p>

<p>Venue: Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[July 2014 Meeting - Nik Molnar and Anthony Van Der Hoorn]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/july-2014-meeting-nik-molnar-anthony-van-der-hoorn"/>
    <updated>2014-06-21T19:26:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/july-2014-meeting-nik-molnar-anthony-van-der-hoorn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talks by Nik Molnar and Anthony van der Hoorn on Wednesday 30th July 2014 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<hr />

<p>Modern Web Development with a Glimpse into ASP.NET</p>

<p>With the state of diagnostics on the web being what it is, we currently have to do a job that is much harder than it should be. Too often, the tools we are provided with only show a small part of the picture, leaving us to guess what else might be happening behind the scenes. Glimpse is an open source project that aims to change the way we think about diagnostics and the frameworks we interact with.</p>

<p>After releasing Glimpse at Mix 11, Glimpse has become a tool that is used daily by tens of thousands of developers around the world. In this session, youíll learn how to use Glimpse to reveal a complete picture of what is happening within your ASP.NET MVC and WebForms sites, discover what tools are included out of the box, and see how you can easily extend it to suit your needs.</p>

<p>Azure Web Sites Secrets, Exposed</p>

<p>Microsoft’s premier cloud solution for custom web applications, Windows Azure Web Sites, has brought the DevOps movement to millions of developers and revolutionized the way that servers are provisioned and applications deployed.</p>

<p>Included with all the headline functionality are many smaller, less-known or undocumented features that serve to greatly improve developer productivity. Join Microsoft MVP and veteran web developer Nik Molnar for a whirlwind tour of these secret features and enhance your cloud development experience.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/aberdeen-developers-net-user-group-july-2014-meeting-tickets-11987774757?ref=ebtnebregn"><img src="https://www.eventbrite.com/custombutton?eid=11987774757" alt="Eventbrite - Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - July 2014 Meeting" /></a></p>

<p>Nik Molnar</p>

<p>Nik Molnar is a New Yorker, Microsoft MVP, ASP Insider and co-founder of Glimpse, an open source diagnostics and debugging tool. Originally from Homestead Florida, Nik specializes in web development, web API&rsquo;s and community management. In his spare time, Nik can be found cooking up a storm in the kitchen, hanging with his wife, speaking at conferences, and working on other open source projects.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>Anthony van der Hoorn</p>

<p>Anthony van der Hoorn is a co–founder of Glimpse, and a regular speaker on such topics as Open Source, Web Practices and Diagnostics for the Web. Anthony has specializing in web and front end development with technologies such as JavaScript, CSS, and HTML. He’s bounced between living and working New York City and his home town of Brisbane, Australia – he’s back in the USA at the moment. Anthony previously worked in the Financial Services sector developing high frequency trading systems and, in his spare time, he can be found out and about taking photos, speaking at conferences, and working on other Open Source projects.</p>

<hr />

<p>Agenda - Wednesday, 30th July 2014</p>

<ul>
<li><p>1800 - 1815: Arrival and registration</p></li>
<li><p>1815 - 1820: Introduction</p></li>
<li><p>1820 - 1900: Modern Web Diagnostics with a Glimpse into ASP.NET</p></li>
<li><p>1920 - 2000: Azure Web Sites Secrets, Exposed</p></li>
<li><p>2000 - onwards: Questions and drinks at the bar</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Prize Draw</p>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes listed <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=107">here</a>.</p>

<p>Location and Directions</p>

<p>Venue: Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB</p>

<p>Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,+Aberdeen,+Aberdeen+City+AB10+7QG,+GB&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=57.119317,-2.136133&amp;spn=0.004165,0.012413&amp;sll=57.746995,-4.687341&amp;sspn=8.392957,25.422363&amp;hq=Faculty+of+Health+%26+Social+Care,+Garthdee+Campus,&amp;hnear=AB10+7QG,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[November 2013 Meeting - Max Vasilyev Talks About Unit Testing]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/november-2013-meeting-max-vasilyev-talks-unit-testing"/>
    <updated>2013-11-03T20:31:57+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aberdeendevelopers.co.uk/november-2013-meeting-max-vasilyev-talks-unit-testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aberdeen Developers are pleased to present a talk by Max Vasilyev on Thursday 17th November 2013 at the Robert Gordon University.</p>

<h2>From zero to 1000 tests in 6 months</h2>

<p>Not every team in the industry is writing automated tests. And it is very difficult to convince everyone on the team and especially business people, that tests must be written.
That initial leap from no tests to some test is the most difficult and many people give up on that stage.</p>

<p>I would like to talk how we managed to jump that gap and started to write tests in our every-day process.
Topics discussed:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>ADD: Annoyance Driven Development</p></li>
<li><p>Isolation Frameworks</p></li>
<li><p>Dependency Injection</p></li>
<li><p>Automocking container</p></li>
<li><p>continuous Integration</p></li>
<li><p>Reflection in tests</p></li>
<li><p>Unit or no unit test?</p></li>
<li><p>Books review</p></li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://adnuguk-nov2013.eventbrite.co.uk/?ebtv=C"><img src="http://www.eventbrite.com/registerbutton?eid=2581657808" alt="Register for Aberdeen Developers .Net User Group - October 2013 Meeting in Aberdeen, Aberdeen City on Eventbrite" /></a></p>

<h2>Speaker Bio</h2>

<p>Max Vasilyev is Senior Developer and QA Manager is Solutions Aberdeen. He have been working with .Net for the last 3 years and before that he worked as a developer in SQL Server.
In the past year he increased his interest in automated testing of the software, as he got very frustrated with constant bugs and shady coding techniques.
So the last year was a constant uphill battle with the business to improve coding quality and increase code test coverage.</p>

<p>The battle is not won yet, but now business agrees that tests are important and any team using Agile must have tests.</p>

<h2>Agenda – Thursday, 21st October 2013</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>1800 - 1815: Arrival and registration</p></li>
<li><p>1815 - 1820: Introduction</p></li>
<li><p>1820 - 2000: From zero to 1000 tests in 6 months</p></li>
<li><p>2000 onwards: Questions and drinks at the bar</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Prize Draw</h2>

<p>All attendees will be entered into a prize draw, with the chance of winning one of the prizes listed <a href="http://www.gep13.co.uk/blog/?p=107">here</a>.</p>

<h2>Location and Directions</h2>

<p>Venue: Riverside East Building, Garthdee Campus, Aberdeen, Aberdeen City AB10 7QQ, GB
Directions: <a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=ab10+7qq&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=57.118536,-2.147655&amp;sspn=0.021179,0.022573&amp;hnear=Aberdeen+AB10+7QQ,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=16">Map showing Garthdee Campus</a></p>

<h2>Slides</h2>

<p>Slides and extra links from the talk are available on <a href="http://tech.trailmax.info/talks/">Max&rsquo;s blog</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
